Finding Aid for Washtenaw County Historic District Commission sound cassettes and summaries, 1965-1981
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Washtenaw County Historic District Commission sound cassettes and summaries
1965-1981
Washtenaw County Historic District Commission.
851731 Cb 2
Oral history interviews with residents of Ann Arbor, Ypsilanti, and other Washtenaw County, Michigan, locales largely concerning their remembrances of their lives and activities during the late nineteenth and early twentieth century.
3 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection came from the organization (donor no. 6127 )
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
The Oral History Project was a volunteer program sponsored by the Washtenaw County Historic District Commission. The purpose was to gather information from long-time county residents that would normally not appear in the written records. The intent was to gather through interviews details about the life and color of a community or an industry or an ethnic group.
The sound recordings were received in different accessions depending mainly on the date of the interview. The first accession was largely made up of interviews conducted by the Ypsilanti Historical Society and related to the history of Ypsilanti and surrounding areas. The second accession is comprised of interviews with individuals relating to Ann Arbor business establishments. The later accessions were miscellaneous interviews on Ann Arbor and Washtenaw County history. Accompanying almost all of the interviews were summary sheets providing a condensation of the interview. The listing below notes the interviews which lack a summary.
The library has releases from about half of the interviewees. Interviews with releases are noted in the listing below.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Commerce.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--History.; Chelsea (Mich.)--History.; Washtenaw County Historic District Commission.; Washtenaw County (Mich.)--History.; Ypsilanti (Mich.)--History.
Subjects - Sound Recordings:
Washtenaw County Historic District Commission.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--History.; Business enterprises--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Chelsea (Mich.)--History.; Business enterprises--Michigan--Washtenaw County.; Washtenaw County (Mich.)--History.; Ypsilanti (Mich.)--History.
Contributors: Sound Recordings
Allen, Ada.; Allen, Mildred.; Allmendinger, Martin.; Anderson, Leigh Charles, 1899-; Barr, Merle.; Becker, Herman.; Biederman, Myrtle.; Bredernitz, Albert.; Bretschneider, Kathryn.; Brewer, Helen.; Buchele, Luther.; Buell, Mahlon.; Burmeister, Marguerite.; Chapman, Katie.; Clague, Ashley, 1902-; Covert, Florence.; Cullis, Hazel, 1888-; Danforth, Percy.; Duff, Lela.; Eberbach, Linda.; Ehnis, Leroy.; Eibler, John.; Eschelbach, Al.; Everett, Franklin.; Forsythe, Russell.; Geisendorfer, George.; Gibson, Audrey.; Gilbert, Mary H.; Graving, William.; Gregory, Charles.; Gregory, Richard C.; Hale, Warren.; Hall, Alice.; Hammond, Ethel.; Hartman, Don.; Hartman, Millie.; Heger, Frank.; Helber, Adolph.; Heller, Ernest.; Hodesh, Mark.; Hoeft, Albert.; Holmes, Blanche R.; Howard, Martin.; Hunnawill, Dorothy.; Hunter, Ruth McCullough.; Keeler, Hugh Blenn, Mrs.; Kelsey, Mike.; Kelsey, Pat.; Kimberly, B. L.; Kinyon, Rachel.; Knapp, Margaret Holsolter.; Lambert, Marguerite Novy.; Latson, Merle D., 1901-; Latson, Ruth.; Lister, Frances.; Lohr, Paul.; Lutz, Arthur.; Lutz, Bert.; Lutz, Betty.; MacDougal, Ron.; McNamee, Robert, 1894-; McOmber, Pearl.; Maroney, Paul.; Marx, LeRoy.; Matthews, Mildred.; Meier, Joy.; Meston, E.; Meyers, Edward H.; Miller, Art.; Morgan, Sam.; Morris, Matilda.; Muehlig, Fay.; Muehlig, Robert.; Muncy, Ralph W. (Ralph Waldo), 1902-; Nielsen, Bent.; Nowland, Chester.; O'Sullivan, James.; Parker, G.; Parr, Clayton.; Patt, Dorothy Wiard.; Pope, Ira Greer, Mrs.; Proud, Paul.; Raab, Doug.; Rash, Ralph.; Reule, Frieda Illi.; Richards, Russell.; Riley, Thomas.; Ross, C. Howard, 1890-1980.; Royce, Ceswell.; Royce, Frank, 1881-; Royce, Lewis.; Russell, Dorothy.; Sager, Herb.; Sallade, George Wahr, 1922-; Sanderson, Harvey.; Satterthwaite, Leroy.; Saxton, Frieda.; Schlenker, Martin.; Smith, Dalene.; Smith, Grace.; Smith, Jim.; Snyder, George.; Steeb, Lloyd.; Steffe, Leah Bolgos.; Strickland, Walter.; Swaine, Jessie.; Tackman, Mildred.; Ulrich, Fred.; Wasem, E.; Weinman, Richard.; Wetherbee, Herbert T., b. 1886.; Weurth, Rose Allmendinger.; Wild, George.; Zeeb, Louise.
Genre Terms:
Oral histories.; Sound recordings.
- Sound cassettes of Interviews
  - Ypsilanti and other topics
    - Baylis, ?. Interviewed by L. Muncy (Box 1)
      (tape no. 1-1)
    - Buell, Mahlon. Interviewed by L. Anderson in Ann Arbor, May 6, 1977 (Box 1)
      (Release)
      (tape no. 1-2)
    - Clague, Ashley (b.1902). Interviewed by Lee Anderson in Ann Arbor, April 20, 1977 (Box 1)
      (tape no. 1-3)
    - Cullis, Hazel (b.1888)., May 29, 1974 (Box 1)
      (Originally recorded by Ypsilanti Historical Society)
      (tape no. 1-4)
    - Eskin, ?. Interviewed by L. Muncy, April 23, 1974 (Box 1)
      (tape no. l-5)
    - Forsythe, Russell. (Box 1)
      (tape no. 1-6)
    - Geisendorfer, George. Interviewed by Tom Lenaghan (Box 1)
      (tape no. 1-6-a)
    - Gilbert, Mary H., July 6, 1969 (Box 1)
      (tape no. 1-7)
    - Hale, Warren. Interviewed by R. Muncy. (Box 1)
      (tape no. l-8)
    - Hall, Alice. Interviewed by L. Muncy, 1974 (Box 1)
      (tape no. 1-9; 1-10)
    - Hammond, Ethel., March 13, 1976 (Box 1)
      (tape no. 1-11)
    - Howard, Martin. Interviewed by R. Muncy, Ann Arbor. (Box 1)
      (tape no. 1-12; 1-13)
    - Hunter, Ruth (McCullough). (on reel with Hazel Cullis), August 16, 1974 (Box 1)
      (tape no. l-4)
    - Klueter, Mrs. Ann Arbor., December 19, 1973 (Box 1)
      (tape no. l-13-a)
    - Knapp, Margaret Holsolter, 1965 (Box 1)
      (tape no. l-14)
    - Knorrp, ?. Manchester. (Box 1)
      (tape no. l-15)
    - Koebbe, Mrs. and her brother Mr. Finch. Interviewed by L. Muncy, November 3, 1976 (Box 1)
      (tape no. l-16)
    - Latson, Merle. Ann Arbor Township., Summer 1977 (Box 1)
      (tape no. 1-17)
    - Lister, Frances., August 20, 1974 (Box 1)
      (tape no. 1-18)
    - Lutz, Arthur. Saline. (Box 1)
      (tape no. 1-19)
    - McNamee, Robert (1894- ). Interviewed by L.C. Anderson. (Box 1)
      (tape no. l-20)
    - McOmber, Pearl. Interviewed by L. Muncy, Ann Arbor. (Box 1)
      (tape no. l-20-a)
    - Marx, Leroy, Marx, Mrs. and Parr, Clayton. Manchester. (Box 1)
      (tape no. l-21; 1-22; 1-23)
    - Matthews, Mildred. (Box 1)
      (tape no. 1-24; 1-25; 1-26)
    - Meston, E., April 12, 1969 (Box 1)
      (tape no. 1-27; 1-28)
    - Meyers, Edward H. Interviewed by Leigh Anderson, Ann Arbor. (Box 1)
      (tape no. 1-29)
    - Nowland, Chester. Interviewed by L. Muncy, Ann Arbor. (Box 1)
      (tape no. 1-30)
    - Parker, G. Interviewed by L. Muncy. (Box 1)
      (tape no. 1-31; tape is blank)
    - Parker, ?. (Box 1)
      (tape no. l-32; 1-33; 1-34)
    - Patt, Dorothy Wiard., 1966 (Box 1)
      (tape no. 1-35; 1-36; 1-37)
    - Pope, Mrs. Ira Greer. Interviewed by L. Muncy, March 20, 1974 (Box 1)
      (tape no. 1-38)
    - Pyle, Shirley. Speech to Ypsilanti Historical Society. (Box 1)
      (tape no. 1-38-a)
    - Richards, Russell. Interviewed by L. Muncy. (Box 1)
      (tape no. 1-39)
    - Riley, Thomas., June 13, 1977 (Box 1)
      (tape no. 1-40)
    - Royce, Frank (1881- ). Interviewed by L.C. Anderson, April 13, 1977 (Box 1)
      (tape no. On tape with Robert McNamee)
      (tape no. 1-20)
    - Sanderson, Harvey. (Box 1)
      (tape no. 1-41)
    - Smith, Grace. Ann Arbor., March 24, 1974 (Box 1)
      (tape no. 1-42; 1-43)
    - Steffe, Leah Bolgos. Interviewed by L. Muncy. (Box 1)
      (tape no. 1-44; 1-45)
    - Swaine, Jessie. (Box 1)
      (tape no. 1-46; 1-47; 1-48; 1-49)
    - Tackman, Mildred., May 1965 (Box 1)
      (tape no. 1-50)
    - Weir, ?. (Box 1)
      (No summary)
      (tape no. 1-51)
    - Wetherbee, Herbert. Interviewed by L. Muncy., April 3, 1974 (Box 1)
      (tape no. 1-52; 1-53)
    - Ypsilanti Historical Society: "EMU is a Bell" (re. history of Eastern Michigan University) (Box 1)
      (tape no. 1-54)
  - Ann Arbor businesses and other topics
    - Allen, Mildred and Ada, August 15, 1975 (Box 2)
      (concerning their lives and family history)
      (tape no. 2-1)
    - Allmendinger, Martin (Box 2)
      (concerning his life and family)
      (tape no. 2-2)
    - Becker, Herman., March 9, 1978 (Box 2)
      (Subjects: Purity Bakery, Heusel's Bakery, Washtenaw Dairy, Ann Arbor Dairy.)
      (tape no. 2-3; 2-4)
    - Biederman, Myrtle., March 15, 1978 (Box 2)
      (Subjects: Farmers' Market, Macks (large department store)
      (tape no. 2-5)
    - Brewer, Mrs. Helen, February 24, 1978 (Box 2)
      (concerning Big Ten Grocery Store)
      (tape no. 2-6)
    - Chapman, Mrs. Katie, April 14, 1978 (Box 2)
      (concerning Chelsea History)
      (tape no. 2-7)
    - Covert, Florence (?) (Box 2)
      (concerning her life)
      (tape no. 2-8)
    - Eberbach, Linda, March 6, 1978 (Box 2)
      (concerning Eberbach Pharmacy and Hardware.)
      4 cassettes
      (duplicate copies available)
      (tape no. 2-9; 2-10; 2-11; 2-12)
    - Ehnis, Leroy, February 17, 1978 (Box 2)
      (concerning Ehnis and Son)
      (tape no. 2-13)
    - Eibler, John, March 13, 1978 (Box 2)
      (concerning Eibler Jewelry)
      (tape no. 2-14)
    - Eschelbach, Al, February 27, 1978 (Box 2)
      (concerning Eschelbach's Meat Market)
      (tape no. 2-15)
    - Graving, Bill, March 2, 1978 (Box 2)
      (concerning Marshall's Drugs. Cassette also includes: Paul Proud, Jr., March 3, 1978, concerning Goodyears and St. James)
      (tape no. 2-16; 2-17)
    - Gregory, Charles, March 1, 1978 (Box 2)
      (concerning Fischer Hardware)
      (tape no. 2-18; 2-19)
    - Gregory, Richard C., August 27, 1980 (Box 2)
      (concerning his life)
      (tape no. 2-20; 2-21)
    - Hartman, Don and Millie, June 12, 1978 (Box 2)
      (Subjects: Hansen's Bakery, C & H Market)
      (tape no. 2-22; 2-23)
    - Heger, Frank, January 6, 1978; May 4, 1978 (Box 2)
      (Duplicate copies available)
      (tape no. 2-24; 2-25; 2-25-a)
    - Helber, Adolph, March 15, 1978 (Box 2)
      Subjects: West Side, Ann Arbor Dairy.
      Cassette also includes Pat and Mike Kelsey, March 22, 1978, concerning Kelsey's Market
      (tape no. 2-26; 2-27)
    - Hodesh, Mark, February 20, 1978 (Box 2)
      (concerning Hertler's Farm Store)
      (tape no. 2-28)
    - Kelsey, Pat and Mike. (Box 2)
      (See Helber, Adolph)
    - Kimberly, B.L., March 19, 1978 (Box 2)
      (concerning Mummery Drugs.)
      Cassette also includes Dalene Smith, January 16, 1978, concerning her life and E. Wassem, January 21, 1978, concerning Farmer's Market.
      (tape no. 2-29; 2-30; 2-31)
    - Lohr, Paul. (Box 2)
      (See Ulrich, Fred)
      (tape no. 2-56; 2-57; 2-58; 2-59)
    - Lutz, Betty and Bert (Box 2)
      (See Muncy, Ralph)
      (tape no. 2-36; 2-37; 2-38)
    - MacDougal, Ron. (Box 2)
      (See O'Sullivan, James)
      (tape no. 2-40; 2-41)
    - Muehlig, Fay, March 7, 1978 (Box 2)
      (concerning Muehlig's Dry Goods)
      (tape no. 2-32; 2-33)
    - Muehlig, Robert (Box 2)
      (concerning Muehlig's Funeral Home)
      (tape no. 2-34)
    - Mummery, ?,., January 1974 (Box 2)
      (tape no. 2-35)
    - Muncy, Ralph, January 20, 1978 (Box 2)
      (concerning a variety of stores and markets. Cassette also includes Betty and Betty Lutz, March 22, 1978, concerning Quality Bakery)
    - Nielson, Bent, November 29, 1977 (Box 2)
      (tape no. 2-39)
    - O'Sullivan, James, February 1, 1978 (Box 2)
      (concerning his ownership of Kroger's.)
      Cassette also includes Ron MacDougal, Feb 1, 1978, concerning Townley's (Food and Drug)
    - Proud. Paul Jr. (Box 2)
      (See Graving Bill)
    - Raab, Doug and Smith, Jim, March 27, 1978 (Box 2)
      (concerning Washtenaw Dairy)
      (tape no. 2-42)
    - Reule, Frieda Illi, May 3, 1978 (Box 2)
      (concerning Illi's Bakeries, Wanty and Reule)
      (tape no. 2-43; 2-44)
    - Ross, C. Howard, March 15, 1977 (Box 2)
      (tape no. 2-45)
    - Royce, Lewis and Ceswell, December 3, 1973 (Box 2)
      (concerning businesses and activities in Ann Arbor)
      (tape no. 2-46)
    - Sager, Herb, February 13, 1978 (Box 2)
      (concerning Fiegel's (Clothing Store))
      (tape no. 2-47)
    - Sallade, George Wahr, February 16, 1978 (Box 2)
      (concerning Wahr's bookstore)
      (tape no. 2-48)
    - Saxton, Frieda. (Box 2)
    - Schlenker, Martin, March 23, 1978 (Box 2)
      (concerning Schlenker's Hardware.)
      Cassette includes Walter Strickland, March 23, 1978, concerning Strickland's Market and George Wild, March 23, 1978, concerning Wild's Men Shop and Wild's Clothing Store.)
      (tape no. 2-49; 2-50; 2-51; 2-52; 2-53)
    - Smith, Dalene. (Box 2)
      (See Kimberly, B.L.)
    - Smith, Jim. (Box 2)
      (See Raab, Doug)
    - Snyder, George, February 24, 1978 (Box 2)
      (concerning Packer's Outlet.
      Cassette also includes Dick Weinmann, February 24, 1978, concerning Weinmann-Geisendorf (meat market); also Fischer Hardware)
      (tape no. 2-54)
    - Steeb, Lloyd, March 27, 1978 (Box 2)
      (concerning Steeb Brothers (meat market))
      (tape no. 2-55)
    - Strickland, Walter. (Box 2)
      (See Schlenker, Martin)
    - Ulrich, Fred, March 14, 1978 (Box 2)
      (concerning Ulrich's Bookstore.
      Cassette also includes Paul Lohr, March 22, 1978, concerning Ann Arbor Implement Company and Frieda Saxton, March 8, 1978, concerning Heusel's Bakery)
    - Wasem, E. (Box 2)
      See Kimberly, B. L.
    - Weinman, Dick. (Box 2)
      (See Snyder, George)
    - Wuerth, Rose Allmendinger, January 1974 (Box 2)
      (tape no. duplicate copy available)
      (tape no. 2-60)
    - Wild, George. (Box 2)
    - Zeeb, Louise (Box 2)
      (tape no. 2-61)
  - Various topics
    - Barr, Mr. and Mrs. Merle, Sr. (Box 3)
      Cassette also includes Kathryn Bretschneider)
      (tape no. 3-1)
    - Beach, Gen. (Box 3)
      (tape no. 3-2)
    - Bredernitz, Albert, June 14, 1977 (Box 3)
      (tape no. 3-3)
    - Bretschneider, Kathryn (Box 3)
      (See Barr, Mr. and Mrs. Merle, Sr.)
    - Buchele, Luther, February 26, 1981 (Box 3)
      (tape no. 3-4)
    - Danforth, Percy, November 23, 1980 (Box 3)
      (tape nos. 3-5; 3-6; 3-7)
    - Duff, Lela, October 26, 1977-November 2, 1977 (Box 3)
      (tape no. 3-8; 3-9)
    - Everett, Franklin, October 26, 1976 (Box 3)
      (tape no. 3-10)
    - Gibson, Mrs. Audrey, January 23-March 2, 1978 (Box 3)
      (tape no. 3-11; 3-12)
    - Gwynner, Mrs. (Box 3)
      (tape no. 3-13)
    - Heller, Ernest., May 4, 1977 (Box 3)
      (tape no. 3-14)
    - Hiscock., January 24, 1974 (Box 3)
      (tape no. 3-15)
    - Kinyon, Rachel. (Box 3)
      (tape no. 3-16)
    - Lambert, Marguerite., January 25, 1978 (Box 3)
      (tape no. 3-17; 3-18)
    - Latson, Ruth., December 11, 1980 (Box 3)
      (tape no. 3-19)
    - Maroney, Mr. and Mrs. Paul., May 5, 1978 (Box 3)
      (tape no. 3-20)
    - Meier, Joy., November 30, 1977; December 7, 1977; March 15, 1978 (Box 3)
      (tape no. 3-21; 3-22)
    - Miller, Art., April 10, 1979 (Box 3)
      (tape no. 3-23)
    - Morgan, Sam., November 8, 1978 (Box 3)
      (tape no. 3-24)
    - Rash, Mr. and Mrs. Ralph., October 14, 1976 (Box 3)
      (tape no. 3-25; 3-26)
    - Russell, Dorothy., November 24, 1980 (Box 3)
      (tape no. 3-27)
    - Satterthwaite, Mr. and Mrs. Leroy. (Box 3)
      (tape no. 3-28)
    - Anderson, Leigh., December 13, 1980 (Box 3)
      (tape no. 3-29)
    - Burmeister, Marguerite., March 10, 1981 (Box 3)
      (tape no. 3-30)
    - Hoeft, Albert, Sr., March 12, 1981 (Box 3)
      (tape no. 3-31; 3-32)
    - Holmes, Blanche R., February 1981 (Box 3)
      (tape no. 3-33)
    - Hunnawill, Dorothy., May 13, 1980 (Box 3)
      (tape no. 3-34)
    - Keeler, Mrs. Hugh (Blenn)., April 6, 1981 (Box 3)
      (tape no. 3-35)
    - Klueter, ?, December 19, 1973 (Box 3)
      (tape no. 3-36)
    - Morris, Matilda., March 6, 1981 (Box 3)
      (tape nos. 3-37; 3-38)
    - Sallade, George., April 27, 1981 (Box 3)
      (tape no. 3-39)